Dhaka, Bangladesh alienpapon009@gmail.com (880) 1625 - 997661

Rathijit Paul

linkedin.com/in/rathijitpapon009/ github.com/rathijitpapon www.rathijitpaul.com

I'm a software developer with experience of 1 year. I'm very much passionate about solving problems, writing efficient codes & developing software tools that will bring automaticity for people. Currently, I'm a final year undergraduate student in Computer Science & Engineering background. Also, I'm a part-time software engineer in a renowned games company.

Work Experience

Junior Software Engineer Free Pixel Games Ltd.

Development team Dhaka, Bangladesh

Feb 2021 - Present

- I'm working with some talented software engineers to build game data-related software and tools.
- I contribute to some data analytics tools that improve our data analysts' workflow & saves their working time.
- I implement efficient algorithms and techniques to improve the performance of game related tools & softwares.
- Often, I give data analytical suggestions for ad management which can generate more revenue.

Software Engineer Intern
Development team

Mainframe Labs Ltd. Dhaka, Bangladesh Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- I have worked with a software developer team to build a live exam website for the students of our country.
- I have contributed to a backend that serves user functionalities to all the microservices of the company applications.
- I have contributed to a OMR sheet scanning system which calculates results from the MCQ answers scripts. It saves a huge time of manual scanning.
- I have learned lots of new technologies, industry standard good practices & team collaborations in software development.

Education and Certifications

B.Sc. Computer Science & Engineering, Bangladesh University of Engineering & Technology

2017 - Present

Technologies and Languages

Languages: Javascript, Python, C++, Java, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

• Technologies: React.Js, Node.Js, Angular, Git, Docker

Other: Data Structures & Algorithms, Full Stack Web Development, Competitive Programming

Projects

- Line Of Action: I have built a web based game called line of action. It's a part of my academic project which intends to implement AI based games using some heuristic algorithms. See the source codes of Line of Action & Live Game.
- **Travel Talk:** I have built a full stack web application Travel Talk which intends to make a social platform for travellers worldwide. See the source codes of Frontend & Backend.
- **Vidly** I have built a full stack movie recommendation web application Vidly. It's a part of my web development learning capstone project. See the source codes on Github.
- Online Judge: I along with a teammate have built a java based ftp application where users can submit the source code for the programming problems & in response the server gives them a verdict like accepted or error. See the source codes on Github.
- Other Projects: I'm regularly building various projects as my university assignments, self learning & contract projects. See them in my Github & Portfolio.

Other Sections

• **Volunteer work** - In my university, I have worked with a club called BUET Career Club for the first 3 years of my university journey. The goal of this club is to help students to assist their future career. Our club arranges so many good seminars, career fairs & extra curricular learning programs every year.

Interests

- My key interest is to build good software systems & machine learning based applications.
- In my personal life, I always love to travel, want to explore different cultures & want to taste various food items.